A Guide to the Women's Suffrage Printed Ephemera Collection, 1860-1917
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
Women's Suffrage Printed Ephemera Collection, 1860-1917
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
M 71
15 items
Collection complied by Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the general collection and purchased from Second Life Books.
Historical Information
The first women's rights meeting in the United States was a social gathering of five women in Seneca Falls, New York in 1848. The women who attended the meeting, Lucretia Mott, Elizabeth Cady Stanton, Mary Ann McClintock, Martha Wright, and Jane Hunt organized a convention at Seneca Falls later the same year that included approximately 300 men and women and set the movement for women's suffrage in full motion. After seven decades of lobbying and outreach by several generations of activists, the 19th Amendment to the Constitution giving women the right to vote was ratified in 1920.
Scope and Content Information
Fifteen printed items were purchased from book dealers in the 1990's. Most of these printed handbills and pamphlets are from the state of New York circa 1917 and before. There are examples of both pro and anti suffrage materials in the collection.
Arrangement
Items arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Advice to Young Ladies, 1860, handbill
  Published in New York by Andrews
- Catholic Opinions, 1900, handbill
  Published in New York by the National Woman Suffrage Association
- Dark and Dangerous Side of Woman Suffrage, undated, pamphlet
  Published in New York by the Women Voters' Anti-Suffrage Party
- Don't Forget to Vote for Woman Suffrage, circa 1917, handbill
  Published in New York by the New York State Woman Suffrage Party
- Extracts from Addresses of the Rt. Rev. Wm. Croswell Doane, June 6, 1894 and June 6, 1895, pamphlet
  Published in New York by the Albany Anti-Suffrage Association
- Few Words in Behalf of the Loyal Women of the United States, undated, booklet
  Published in New York by the Loyal Publication Society
- How to Vote for Woman Suffrage Amendment, Election Day, November 6th, 1917, handbill
- Protest Against the Granting of Municipal Suffrage to Women, Chicago, 1906, booklet
  Published in Chicago by the Association Opposed to the Extension of Suffrage to Women
- Think It Over, Michigan, undated, postcard
  Published by Cargill Company for the National American Woman Suffrage Association
- Votes for Women! The Woman's Reason, undated, handbill
  Published in New York by the New York State Woman Suffrage Association
- Why New York Men Should Give New York Women the Vote, 1917, pamphlet
  Published in New York by the Empire State Campaign Committee
- Why Working Women Want the Vote, Mass Meeting...to Celebrate Passage of Suffrage Amendment by Legislature, April 3, 1917, handbill
- Women in the Home, undated, handbill
- Woman Suffrage Above Human Law. Letter from Gerrit Smith to Susan B. Anthony, August 15, 1873, handbill
- Your Vote, 1917, handbill